Every once in a while,
I go public with the feedback
that I'm giving people in my
mentorship.
And if you want me to critique the content
that you're putting out,
there's a link in the description.
Click on that, give me your details.
I'll get into it in the next round.
I've just cracked a can of tonic,
and I'm ready
to give a roasting. Now,
first thing I'm doing
is I'm having a bit of an argument
with someone. So this
is my best performing reel in quite a
while, and this is the
point I want to draw him to. Brother,
my best performer.
Note what happens in the first 10 seconds.
One in three people leave.
That's being kind. That's my best video.
The majority of people exit your content
within literally a few seconds.
Something as simple as starting your video
with, "Yes, people.
So today we're go-" They're gone. You sit,
you take a moment in front of the
camera, you say,
"Imagine a world where you could eat more
meals, lose more fat,
and improve your 5K time without having to
give up sausages.
Let's get into it." And then
if you sit there and think, "Oh,
that wasn't good
enough," you just go back into it again.
"Imagine if you could eat sausages
and still lose fat.
Well,
this study from 1992 showed this could be
possible if you do one thing.
But before we get into that one thing,
we need to appreci-- Yes, people,
welcome to
the edit." No. Okay,
let's get back to what we're supposed to
be doing.
Just made a video on reacting to a fitness
creator who covers a scale number with a
number they want to see.
Let's just get into it, shall we, son?
I'm all about people reacting to other
reels,
but the one thing I will say here is
sometimes you need to preface what it
is you're reacting to.
So for instance,
you could just come front and center
and go, "You're not going to
believe this." Then you get into this.
Just something that shows me
that there's a react coming,
because I feel like I'm
watching the original.
[upbeat music]
Captain out.
Okay.
I like this idea of what you're doing
here.
A little bit slow to get into.
So far we're what?
Six, seven seconds in, no context.
Altitude's a little low.
Could you give me the controls
and I'll go higher?
Don't worry about that, mate. No, no.
Just think too many people have left.
Here we make our own happiness, yeah?
We've always got to optimize our content
for a cold audience.
We've always got to think about people not
knowing us, not liking us, so we
have to be very mindful of their time.
This takes a little bit too long to get
going.
Most people would have left, I'm afraid.
Okay, we've got James Ollie here.
Let's check out this one.
To get in great shape this summer,
throw the body weight scales out-
Okay, so we're opening with a good hook.
This stock image of someone with the
scales.
Out of the window. They're useless.
Your body weight fluctuates.
Okay, let's start this again.
Great shape this summer.
Throw the body weight scales out-
You could have bought the cheapest scales
online and you could have thrown them out
a window.
Let's say you've even got some £10 Amazon.
Then straight away in the first few
seconds,
I've seen someone lob some scales.
For you, that costs £10,
but you're raising the stakes to another
level of content
where people go, "Wow,
this person's put a lot of effort into
this."
Out of the window. They're useless.
Your body weight fluctuates sev-
This layer over as well
is also making it a little bit harder to
read your captions
... or kilograms in any 24-hour period.
A better alternative
is to measure your body fat.
But which device is best to do this?
Did we swap audio there between cameras?
A lot of people use the foot-to-foot
bioelectrical
impedance body fat scales, but these
are a waste of time because
electricity takes the shortest route
and they measure just the body fat of
your inner thighs. Far better is to get-
I think we would have had to have brought
some science here, something to
say to us, "Okay, they're inaccurate.
Have you got receipts for that?
Have we got data to show that?
How inaccurate are they?"
The Tanita body fat scales
that include your hands and the-
Again, this overlay here,
maybe this could have just been B-roll of
footage
of people using that. If this visual
is so important, why
is it just a third of the
screen?
And that way the current runs through your
whole body giving you a much more
accurate measurement
and letting you know where you
are in terms of progress.
Because these are coming up far too quick
and am I looking at you?
Am I looking at these? What am I doing?
Oh, and it's over.
A subject like this I think could have
been best done on YouTube maybe.
This is really what I think we should have
done here.
You could have come here
and watched this video first.
I tested seven body fat scales
and DEXA scans here's the most accurate.
You could have just watched this guy's
video and potentially made your own
version
of it.
When people-
Now what a lot of people do is,
no offense to this guy,
but I'm not watching your
video, brother.
Most people come over here,
they copy the transcript, they go to
ChatGPT, they say summarize at the bottom,
and whilst they take a sip of tonic.
So we can actually see the different
percentages differences here.
So I feel like there should have
potentially been a bit more research done.
The overlay to me
was a bit overkill instead of overlay.
So if you want to get in great shape this
summer, show away the body weight scales.
We didn't actually talk about getting in
good shape.
I would just say scales
are a waste of money. Throwing them out.
That could have been a visual hook as long
as with a natural hook.
Or we should have just got the scales with
the bioelectrical impedance on
and go,
"If you're standing on these in the
morning trying to determine how much
fat you have, you're wasting your time
and I'm going to explain why." This has
nothing to do with getting in good shape.
That's the only issue.
So let me give you that feedback. This
is why I like typing on the Discord
because
actually the feedback I'm giving
is sometimes easier to type than it
is to say.
And something I've just said here
is rather than having all of this overlay,
we
should have had some kind of analogy
or a prop or been like, "If we
were to pass
electricity through this bottle we
could..." Or whatever it is.
We should have given a visual
representation,
not just gone to Google Images and
overlaid something.
Because quite frankly it's just a little
bit lazy.
And that's fine,
but you can't cry about the results you
didn't get with the work
you didn't do. Okay, here we go, Leo.
I already know Leo last time
was talking about something
and he had the fucking
thing he was talking about behind him.
There's a hierarchy of importance
and right now I can already see
if he's talking
about something, if it's in front of you,
it's more important.
Yep.
Can you drink alcohol
and still make progress in the gym?
This is quite messy.
The font is very difficult to see because
of what we have behind it.
So maybe we did need to put a little bit
of behind that, but okay.
Let's listen.
Make progress in the gym? Well,
the answer's yes, but also no.
This is a double shot of 50 milliliters of
Jack Daniel, and this is
16 grams of salted butter.
Now both of these have the same amount of
calories.
Good visual representation. I like this.
I like that.
I'm actually seeing like, oh,
if I wasn't to drink at dinner, suddenly I
can have a lot more butter on my
sourdough. You're talking my language,
son.
Because alcohol contains seven calories
per gram and fat contains nine
calories per gram. And the truth
is you'd be much better off ditching the
booze and
sticking with the butter because at least
fat has some nutritional content.
Fat's good for hormone production for
Like what you say there,
nutritional value,
good for hormone production.
Garbage.
Like what hormone production?
A very easy opportunity there to go into a
little bit
more detail.
It's just empty calories,
and it provides no nutrition whatsoever.
So not only does alcohol contain empty
calories,
but the body actually prioritizes
metabolizing alcohol before it does fat.
This is because alcohol is a poison
and your body wants to get rid of it as
soon as
possible. So if you go on a night out
and you get on the booze and you go
and get a
greasy kebab, what's going to happen
is the alcohol's going to get burnt off
first,
and the kebab is more likely to be stored
as fat as opposed to if you just had it
when you were sober. So even
if you track every single Baby Guinness
that you have
for the night and put it into
MyFitnessPal,
you might stay in a calorie deficit and
still end up with more fat on your body
because your body's going to be
prioritizing burning off that-
Leo, I like this,
and I've been giving you some shit
recently, brother.
So this is big. This is great. Love this.
Much better. Really good.
Could have delved into those hormones.
What an improvement.
Because I ain't going to lie to you,
I'm pretty sure, off the
top of my head,
I caught Leo doing a flipping leg press
video in a PureGym
top. I said, "Brother, no." Sorry,
just delving out a bit of tough love
there.
Sometimes you've just got to hit people in
the face.
Say to them,
"Why the fuck would I hire you
and not someone else?" It's a tough
question for people. Bro,
you can flip that onto me.
Why hire me and not someone else?
It's a good question.
But let me tell you this.
I don't lie. I'll give it to you straight.
Sometimes my feedback has been called
chemotherapy because it takes you as close
as
you can to dying,
but it's there to save you.
And remember,
although sometimes I am a ruthless,
horrible twat,
in my eyes,
the worst thing I could ever say to
someone is, "Yeah, mate, content
looks good, mate.
Crack on." That's the worst thing I could
say.
Stuck learning new skills for months
or even years?
This video is for you. I'll give you-
Let's try this again.
I think I got absolutely nothing from that
... stuck learn-
If you've been stuck
... learning new skills
Learning new skills. Like a muscle-up
or just skills in general?
For months or even years
Months or even years.
That's not very specific.
If you were to say,
"If you still can't do a muscle-up,
then this video is for
you," I'm in. But that was fucking vague,
mate
... you is free.
I'll give you my five-step framework to-
I don't care. What is it this video
is about?
... unlock new skills-
What new skills, brother?
... faster and without spending-
Bro, get to the fucking point, please
... extra hours in the gym. Step-
Oh, so this skill-based... Bro,
I don't know what this is about
... one, set one specific goal. Let's-
For what, brother?
What am I setting a specific goal for?
...
take the strict ring muscle-up as an ex-
Okay,
so we're talking about the ring muscle-up.
Why didn't you just fucking say
that in the hook?
Step two, are you lacking strength or
are you lacking mobility?
For example,
with the strict ring muscle-up,
you need to be able to pull you to
your chest and have a deep ring-
For this, why not just say,
"If you're struggling doing ring
muscle-ups,
try doing this. Number one,
instead of trying to do a muscle-up,
instead just build
the strength necessary to get your chest
to touch the rings." Too many people doing
a ring muscle-up don't have the strength
to do a strict chin-up, yet they're trying
to do the full thing together.
That's something where I go, "Oh,
do you know what?
I'm going to go into the gym,
and even though I know I can't do a ring
muscle-up,
I'm just going to try
and do ring-to-chest flipping chin-ups."
Yeah.
Then you're going to dedicate two to-
Because the information here you have is
good and needed.
It's just poorly portrayed
...
three sessions of 15 to 20 minutes on that
specific skill.
The timeframe will depend on your starting
point.
The intro is so vague, mate.
I have no idea what it's about.
You need to mention ring muscle-ups in
your intro, not new
skills,
and you need to deliver one actionable
point much faster.
Because go watch it back. It's slow, bro.
I don't even know what you're on about for
ages.
Should have opened with...
Needs a bit of work, brother.
Can be anywhere from 6 to 12 weeks
or even more.
But your skill work should always be done-
Do me a favor. Next time you make content,
I feel like people are trying to
talk to professionals.
It's like LinkedIn garbage where people
are like, "Yeah, so
moving forward,
I think there could be an opportunity for
us to touch base.
Why don't we just pencil something
into..." Why don't you just say, "Yo,
let's
fucking get on a call one day,
you cunt." "Yeah, sweet." If you
were talking to a
kid, you'd say, "Hey, you can't do
that yet.
But if you do this first
and you can show mommy
and daddy you can do that,
we'll let you do that." That's,
in essence, what we're doing here.
Hey, if you can't do this,
you can't do that.
So why don't you just work on
that three times a week?
Not 15 to 20 minutes.
Just do it three times a week.
I don't care how fucking long it takes
you. Oh, yeah? Here's one for you.
Charles Poliquin, who just makes shit up,
used to say to people, "Oh, you can't do
a concentric chin-up,
so you can do a 30-second eccentric." He
just made it up.
But it got people doing fucking
eccentrics,
which helped them with their strength.
All right, Scotty2Hotty in the house.
Fucking cling film. All of the surfaces.
My God.
See to set up and talk at the same time.
It's tough.
[laughs] For fucking hell.
If it's not cling film, any tattoo
artist will know.
They will tell you fucking bane of their
existence is getting
cling film off the fucking roll
and getting this white tape off.
Okay, I'm 20 seconds in,
and I don't know what this is about, mate.
I got 20 seconds into this without knowing
what it's about.
Why can I ask we chose to do this?
It's all well and good making
content for your followers,
but you also want to make content to
people that have
never, ever seen your shit before, ever.
Like even this video right now,
wherever you're seeing it,
I would like to think if
you've never seen my face before,
you can go, "That's quite helpful."
But I'm not
in here talking about my car
or my sauna or what I'm getting up to
today because
you don't care.
You just want to know how you can do
better.
So that to me, I gave you 20 seconds,
Scotty, and I'm busy.
I've got a busy Discord of stuff to get
through.
I'm not going to give you any more.
And you pay me, bro.
You pay my bills. You bought that car.
And I'm not giving you any more time.
So a cold audience are giving you nothing,
nada.
From this to this and stay
that way for the rest of your life,
you need to start
doing these five things right now.
Hmm. Okay. It's not bad.
The diplomas in the background, little bit
cringe-worthy, but you sound American,
so I could let you off because you guys
might just love that shit, man.
Number one, optimize-
Okay, right. Let's start this again.
When people say,
"Do these five things," they're trying to
retention hack a bit where they go,
you get the first one, you're like, "Oh,
I'll
stay for the other four." But just say,
"Just do these things," and then give me
five. Because sometimes I watch this,
I go, "Five things?" I go,
"I ain't got time,
brother.
I need to swipe past this so I can look at
a Porsche GT3 RS do
a burnout,
or I can swipe again to see someone
slipping on ice, or I can swipe
again and see a really cute story about a
dog being rescued." So when you go, "I've
got five things," I go, "Bro,
I'm on Instagram.
I ain't got time for five things." But
if you just started reeling them out,
fine.
From this to this and stay
that way for the rest of your life,
you need to start
doing these-
And you're not far off, bro.
You're a good-looking guy.
You got potential
Five things right now
And I hate this,
"Just do these five things." Because you
wouldn't say that to your
friend. "Hey, bro, let's go out.
We're going to get five tacos
tonight at the bar.
Then we're going to have two beers." You
wouldn't be like that.
You'd be like,
"Let's just get five tacos
and get a couple beers." Talk to me like
I'm a friend.
Number one, optimize sleep hygiene.
Okay. Optimize sleep hygiene.
What does that mean?
If I'm watching this
and I needed to wake up today and go,
"Fucking hell, I didn't
know that." If you just walk past someone
who's not sleep enough, "Optimize sleep
hygiene." They're, "Oh, fucking hell,
thanks for that, mate. Fucking wonderful.
How did I not think of
that before?" You could be getting into
it.
If you don't get seven to nine hours of
quality sleep, you're cooked.
Energy's going down, hunger's going up,
and you're just going to have a bad day.
If you want the best quality of sleep,
keep your room pitch black or use an eye-
Okay, I take that back. I like that.
Pitch black, like the eye mask
... mask.
Keep your room temp around 66 to 72
degrees Fahrenheit.
And lastly,
control the noise with earplugs
or a white noise maker.
Number two is stay-
Okay, I take that back. I
was completely wrong. You were right.
I eat shit.
But maybe just open with that.
Don't say optimize sleep hygiene because
people
don't know what that is. Just say,
"Did you know wearing an eye mask
and blocking
out light and noise
and getting your temperature right can
help you sleep better,
which means you can eat less?"
Hydrated. Take your body weight
and divide it by two.
Then take it again
and multiply it by point-
It's not a fucking maths lesson, mate.
It's not a fucking maths lesson
... 66. That'll be the range of
fluid ounces you need in a day.
How about this? If your piss stinks
or it's yellow, drink a bit more water.
If you're pissing all the time,
you're having too much
... of a bottle and chug away.
Number three, set a standard of fitness.
Strength and conditioning
are non-negotiable.
You can do weight-
What is a standard of fitness?
It's body weights, conditioning.
Three to four sessions a week
is a sweet spot for a good level of
fitness.
Sprinkle any type of movement you can,
like walking or some form of mobility
drills, to keep you nice
and limber as you age.
Number four, build-
Would've liked a little bit more there,
maybe like a step count to work towards,
maybe a 5K time that people should aspire
for.
But yeah
... good eating habits.
Your eating patterns should center around
quality calories.
What are quality calories?
This means learning what whole,
minimally processed foods are.
Okay. Thank you
...
discovering where you can personally get
them, taking the time to learn how to
prepare them in a way
that you actually enjoy, all
while still not getting-
Okay, it's actually not that bad.
What's the feedback I'm going to give?
I like this.
I feel each point could have been its own
video.
And that's the thing.
Don't compress everything together.
Spread it out. More volume,
less intensity. There you go.
Putting it in fitness chat for the bro.
Keep pumping.
Oh,
we also need to look at his bio because
before there was nothing in his bio.
Right,
that is the wrong picture for fitness.
You need a new DP.
You look like you're selling real estate.
Hopefully DP you'll know
that means display picture,
not double penetration.
And these, no idea what these mean.
What's the point?
Just say what you do, bro.
Like putting letters after your name,
you're just trying
to impress other people with a
qualification. This isn't bad.
I help people. Yeah, cool.
Like fucking when I go to the doctor,
I just
want some antibiotics for the staph
infection in my leg. That's all I want.
If the doctor comes out and goes, "Yeah,
I'm an RDN, CSC," bro, I don't care.
Just write the fucking script.
I got staph, brother.
I haven't, but when I do get staph,
saving time when we see a doctor.
Just like, just fucking get on with it,
mate. You know what I mean?
You know what I mean? Okay, cool. Right.
This content section is finished.
Thank you